once the carnal mind takes over there is
a filter that is placed on it that says
yeah god you're in the you're a
vindictive God that's why I have to hide
because you know I'm afraid you might
kill me it says here the indulgence of
lustful appetite wars against the soul
it is a constant hindrance to spiritual
advancement those who yield to these
lower impulses bare and accusing
conscience and when straight truths are
presented if they are ready to take
offence they are self condemning and
think that the subjects have been
purposely selected in order to reprove
them they feel grieved and injured and
withdraw themselves from the Assemblies
of the church then the conscience is not
so disturbed
thus they soon lose their interest in
the meetings and their love for truth
and their love for truth if these will
crucify fleshly lusts the arrows of
truth will pass harmlessly by them but
while they indulge lustful appetite and
thus cherish their idols they make
themselves a mark for the shafts of
truth if the truth is spoken at all it
must wound them today I'm pleading with
you guys there may be some of you in
here today who are thinking well I know
he's not talking to me he probably wants
us to hit me no move out the way move
out of the way today Satan gets revealed
amen Heavenly Father as we begin this
message I pray Lord that we will all
have that aha moment I pray Lord that we
will see how it is the devil seeks to
come in and destroy relationships
destroy friendships destroy Brotherhood
and sisterhood help our eyes to be open
Lord and help us to recognize that we do
not wrestle against flesh and blood
but against spiritual wickedness in high
places in Jesus name we pray amen
I want to let you know right up front
that at the end of this message I'm
going to have an appeal it is gonna be a
very pointed appeal and I believe that
if you respond to this appeal you will
see God working in your life in ways
that you could not have imagined General
Lee's special orders 191 have you ever
heard of General Lee's special orders
191 generally had made plans during one
of his Maryland campaigns during his
Maryland campaign wrote those plans out
generally and the South had been beating
the north at every step and and after
one particular battle some northern
soldiers were crossing this battlefield
that a battle had just taken place and
they sat under a tree because they were
discouraged and as they looked over to
to the side of them they notice that
there was an envelope and the envelope
had three cigars in it one of the
soldiers took the envelope opened it and
discovered General Lee's battle plans it
is said that that single event changed
the tide of the battle George be
McClellan the commander of the Army
Potomac was overcome with glee at
learning at learning the plan
Confederate troops movement and
reportedly exclaimed now I know what to
do
he confided to a brigadier general Gen
given here is a paper in which if I
cannot wait Bobby Lee I will be willing
to go home but ever what would you do
what would you give to have the enemy's
plan for your life what would you give
to be able to see ah this is what he's
up to this is what he's up to in my life
this is what he's up to in my
relationships this is what he's up to
in my
Church in my churches what would you do
to be able to see behind the scenes of
the devil's battle plan but other what
I'm gonna show you today is the devil's
battle plan and let me tell you in a way
I want you all to get out the way but in
a way we are all in the way because in a
way you will see guess what all of us
have at one time or another been duped
by Satan's plan are you with me so what
is the devil's plan if I were to
summarize this sermon right now in a 40
second clip this would be there's some
church members I mean some animals and
you got other church members that are
just like man look at them golf and then
they dip I mean they leave without even
warning they're just like I'm gone let
me ask you a question the Bible says be
sober be vigilant because your adversary
the devil as a roaring lion walketh
about seeking whom he may devour beloved
listen to me if I could summarize the
enemy's plan in 140 second video this
would be it because if the enemy can get
us to be fighting with one another
lonna me ask you a question you need to
see this alright so here we got brother
against brother or gazelle against
whatever they were right let me ask you
did anyone cheer for the animal that got
caught was anyone like yes he's caught
the devil the lion got him what were
they busy doing were they busy
what were they busy doing fighting okay
what do you think they were fighting
over a girl power
territory all right now whatever it was
in gazelle world we were looking at it
from outside we're going what in the
world was the fight worthy no but in in
gazelle world the fight was worthy and
and in that fight they could not see
what was coming because they were busy
looking at each other had to whisper
that for effect this is what they were
busy doing now let me ask you a question
all guilty parties please raise your
hand if you've ever done this before
come on guys come on you know how it can
be we know the Bible says we wrestle not
against flesh and blood but sometimes we
look at flesh and blood listen to me
every person in God's church is
important and needed some people every
person in God's church is important and
needed every person in God's church has
special talents and special gifts that
God has brought to this church for a
reason and everyone is needed even when
you think I don't have a gift and
because of that Satan hates and wants to
destroy every person in God's church or
God's kingdom why because every person
in God's church or God's kingdom is
needed everybody how do you spell
everything you know how to spell every
every do I need to emphasize that more
everyone is needed in the kingdom of God
and so Satan hates
anyone who is seeking to the will of God
or seeking to be in God's kingdom so
listen what I'm gonna show you is this
is how the devil this is how he operates
and beloved it's it's bone-chilling get
out of the way save with me everyone one
two three get out of the way in the
beginning God had a creation plan God
had a what every one creation plan
Genesis 1:26 God said let us make man in
our what's in our image and in our
likeness so God's plan was to create
mankind but the devil got jealous of
that plan is that correct Isaiah 14 how
art thou fallen from heaven o Lucifer
son of the morning how art thou cut down
to the ground which didst weaken the
nation's for thou hast said in thine
heart I will ascend into heaven I will
exalt my throne above the stars of God I
will sit also upon the Mount of the
congregation in the sides of the north I
want to send about the heights of the
clouds I will be like the Most High what
was Satan after he was after power he
was after position he was after
authority this is what he wanted he was
jealous that he was not a part of God's
creation plan with his son anyone know
what the name Lucifer means what does it
mean Lucifer means Light Bearer
I want you to keep the meaning of that
name in mind
Lucifer his name means what everyone
light there what does the Light Bearer
do shines what shines light shines like
very good he was to shine light and he
was to reflect the glory of of God okay
very good check this out Ezekiel 28 the
Bible says by the multitude environment
of thy merchandise speaking of Lucifer
by the multitude of thy merchandise they
even word their Ricola it means trade by
the multitude of thy merchandise or
trade they have filled the Mississippi
with violence and thou has sinned so
what was Lucifer doing in heaven
he was merchandising he was trading and
if you're trading that makes you a
traitor you're not feeling me Lucifer
was a traitor amen
that's what he was doing in heaven he
was trading what was he trading that's
the question
he was trading lies he was trading
deceit now check this out guys you have
to see this because according to Anna
Anna praise God as a church we have
special insight into what happened in
heaven because let me tell you when we
see what happened in heaven we can know
Satan's plan we can know that he doesn't
change the same thing he did in heaven
is the same thing he'll try to do on
earth so watch this oh here's that
speaking of Lucifer all his acts were so
clothed with mystery that it was
difficult to disclose the true nature of
his work even the loyal angels could not
fully discern his character or see to
what his work was leading guys I'm not
not talking about bad angels right the
Angels that for whatever reason you know
kind of like whatever with God I'm
talking about good angels is anyone here
who considers them a good considers
themself a good person okay I know
that's a trick question
you know there is none good but one I
get it I get it but I'm not talking
about that I'm just saying you consider
yourself I believe that I am a moral
person I'm striving to do good right I'm
not how trying to do evil right I don't
think there is anyone in our church here
that is tried that there's no we don't
have a Satan in our church are you with
me we don't have people that are like I
would like I love evil let's do some
evil anybody wanted we don't have that
here I believe that what we have here
are people who are seeking to do good
and that's in every church I believe
people are are genuinely like we we want
to do good but check this up even the
your angels could not discern fully the
work of who Satan his character his
nature they could everything he shrouded
in mystery and by artful perversion cast
doubt upon the plainest statements of
God and his high position gave greater
force to his representations listen to
this Satan is the leader of every
species of rebellion today as he was the
originator of rebellion in the courts of
heaven standing next to Christ in power
and glory
yet he coveted the honor that belonged
to the son he desired to be equal with
God to carry out his purpose he
concealed his true designs from the
angels and worked deceptively to secure
their allegiance and honor to himself by
sly insinuations by which he made it
appear that Christ had assumed the place
that belonged to him Lucifer sowed the
seeds of walks doubt in the minds of
many of the angels and when he had won
their support he carried the matter to
God declaring that it was a sentiment of
many of the heavenly beings that he
should have the preference to Christ so
here's my question
who did Lucifer have an issue with so
what did he do
who did he go to okay hold on he had an
issue with who so he went to who wait a
minute
doesn't the Bible tell us we're talking
about Satan's plan of operation right
get out the way guys same with him
everyone get out the way amen this is
just to help you all get out the way
okay if you have an issue in Christ what
do you do you go to him but what didn't
Lucifer do he went to the Angels so look
who did he go to first he went to the
angels and then who did he go to
afterward then he went to Christ then he
went to God you see how Satan operates
wait guys we're not on earth right now
we are we are angels in heaven
imagination okay
we are in heaven before earth has been
created and we're watching this unfold
and we're going whoa look at what
Lucifer's doing we're talking about
Satan's battle plans so so listen
Lucifer went out to spread the spirit of
discontent among the angels for a time
he hid his real purpose under an
appearance of reverence for God suddenly
he planned - doubts concerning the laws
that govern heavenly beings suggesting
that angels needed no such rules for
their own wisdom was a sufficient guide
all their thoughts were holy it was no
more possible for them to do wrong than
for God himself to error this the
exaltation of the Son of God as equal
with the father was made to appear as an
injustice to Lucifer if the Prince of
Angels could only attain to this to his
true exalted position great good would
come to the entire horse of heaven for
it was his purpose to secure freedom for
all subtle deceptions through the wicked
schemes of Lucifer were quickly growing
in the heavenly courts do you see how
Lucifer was beginning to sow discord
among God's angels so Lucifer what does
it mean Light Bearer
when Lucifer's sin was he still alive
better was he still alive error is he
still alive bearer
is Lucifer still a light bearer but what
kind of light barrier is he false lights
Lucifer's superpower you guys get out of
the way please do not defend Satan it up
in this place today
Lucifer's superpower is false
like the true position of the Son of God
had been the same from the beginning
however many of the angels were blinded
by Lucifer's deception he's so artfully
instill into their minds his own
distrust and discontent that they did
not recognize what he was doing let me
ask you question is he still doing that
today okay I'm not talking about people
get out of the way is he still doing
that today so hold on if Satan hates you
if Satan hates you will he seek to put
his thoughts of you in other people's
minds Lucifer had presented the purposes
of God you know what what is what is
Lucifer's super power false lights
Lucifer had put the purposes of God in a
false light to excite dissent and
dissatisfaction while he claimed to be
perfectly loyal to God he urged that
changes were necessary for the stability
of the divine government while secretly
stirring up conflict and rebellion he
made it appear that his only purpose was
to promote loyalty and to preserve
harmony and peace let me ask you from
looking at what he did in heaven do you
believe that Satan seeks to do the same
thing today in our relationships in our
families with our friends in our
churches what do you think get out of
the way guys this is not about you
this is not
about me this is about revealing the
plan of the enemy get out of the way
you know what filters are right how many
instagramers we have here or yeah you
you know what it what a filter is right
a filter changes your perception of the
picture a filter changes the color of
the picture do you think Satan has
filters when the Angels began sharing
false light they became false light
bearers became as Lucifer himself
Lucifer was trading false light did you
catch that
what Lucifer began to do in heaven was
put a put a filter over the minds of
angels so that when they looked at God
they were like hmm I hadn't seen that
before and now anytime they turned their
eyes to look at God because they were
looking at God through a particular
filter all they saw was what Lucifer
told them so what should Lucifer have
done what would have stopped what would
have possibly stopped this rebellion in
heaven Matthew 18:15
moreover if thy brother shall trespass
against thee go and tell him his fault
between V and him alone if he shall hear
thee thou has gained thy brother but if
he will not hear thee then take it to
with with - with take with thee one or
two more that in the mouth of two or
three witnesses every word may be
established and if you neglect to hear
them tell it unto the Lord what didn't
Lucifer do first he went to the he went
to the angels first then he said now now
let's go to God was Lucifer interested
in reconciliation
like whatever his issue was with God or
God you know he's a mean whatever
was he really interested in
reconciliation no no guys I want to say
something to you right now get out of
the way get out of the way are you out
of the way if you're out of the way just
let me see your hands right now right if
no one's thinking you talk about please
I just wanna see because I'm not talking
about you I'm not talking about flesh
and blood I'm talking about Satan
himself listen
so the Savior gathered his disciples
about remember the disciples were having
issues with each other what was their
issue who's going to be the greatest
yeah yeah so the Savior gathered his
disciples about him and said to them if
any man desire to me first the same
shall be last of all and servant of all
there was in these words a solemnity and
impressiveness with which the disciples
were far from comprehending that Christ
discerned they could that which Crisis
earned they could not see they did not
understand the nature of Christ's
Kingdom and this ignorance was the
apparent cause of their contention but
the real cause lay deeper by explaining
the nature of the kingdom Christ might
for a time have quelled their strife but
this would not have touched the under
lying cause even after after they had
received the fullest knowledge any
question of precedence might have
renewed the trouble
thus disaster would have been brought to
the church after Christ's departure let
me ask you what is it that brings
disaster to Christ Church precedence
supremacy striving this strife for the
highest place was the out working of the
same spirit which was beginning which
was the beginning of the great
controversy in the worlds above and
which had brought Christ we have him to
die there rose up before him a vision of
Lucifer the son of the morning in glory
surpassing all the angels that
surrounded the throne and United in
closest ties to the Son of God Lucifer
has said I will be like the Most High
and the desire for self exaltation had
brought strife into the heavenly courts
and had banished a multitude of the
hosts of God had Lucifer really desire
to be like the Most High he would never
have deserted his appointed place in
heaven for the Spirit of the Most High
is manifested in unselfish ministry
Lucifer desired God's power but not his
character he suffered himself the
highest place and every being who is
actuated by his spirit will do the same
thus really with together with me
everyone thus alienation discord and
strife will be what what's that word
inevitable Dominion becomes the prize
with the strongest the kingdom of Satan
is a kingdom of force every individual
is regarded regards every other as an
obstacle in the way of his own
advancement or stepping-stone on which
he himself may climb to a higher place
get out of the way get out of the way
this is not about you or you or you or
you or you or you or you this is we are
in a war room right now no no no let me
turn this way because I don't want to be
like I'm sorry we are in a war room
right now and we are looking for that
Satan's plan what would you follow me
this is a war room right now this is
God's warm right now and God is
revealing to us how the enemy seeks to
disrupt the work he wants his church to
do so you know the story Lucifer and his
angels are cast out of heaven and and
now Lucifer turns his sight on Adam and
Eve and guess what he does
what is his super power fast light
Genesis 3:1 now the serpent was more
subtle than any beast of the field which
the Lord God had made and he said unto
the woman yea hath God said what is he
doing what he's merchandise what is he
merchandising fast luck he's saying look
I know how you see God but but I have
something to tell you about him and once
check this out the serpent said unto the
woman you shall not surely die for God
does know that in the day you eat
thereof then your eyes shall be opened
he shall be as God's knowing good and
evil
what had he effectively done with Adam
and Eve he put a filter on their minds
yeah whoa man thank you for opening my
eyes yeah I didn't catch that just now
did you thank you for opening my eyes
the eyes of them both were what open and
they knew that they were when they
sinned their eyes were opened they heard
the voice of the Lord God walking in the
garden in the cool of the day and Adam
and his wife and his wife hid themselves
God comes looking for them they say we
hid because we were rocks okay pause for
a second check this out what else did he
say
the woman that you okay watch this were
their eyes open before they sinned where
Adam and Eve's eyes open before they
sing what do you think yes or no yes let
me see your hands their eyes are open
before they sin
no let me see your hands their eyes were
not open okay you're both right they
could not have seen the tree if their
eyes weren't open so the I what do you
how many of you ever said yes see what
you're talking about
what does that mean I see what you're
saying I was I understand so an Adam and
Eve's sin guess what eyes were open the
carnal mind that's what got opened look
look Romans 8:7 the carnal mind is what
enmity against God for it is not what
subject the law of God neither indeed
candy when Adam and Eve sinned the
carnal mind was open now do you think
the carnal mind has filters so watch
this when the loving beautiful amazing
gracious merciful compassionate God of
heaven comes to the garden looking for
Adam and Eve what do they do
what is in the very fact that they are
hiding what are they doing they're
accusing God of being someone who is
unapproachable once the carnal mind
takes over there is a filter that is
placed on it that says yeah God um
you're in the you're a vindictive God
that's why I have to hide because you
know I'm afraid you might kill me so I
can't really talk to you if there's an
issue the woman the woman what so who's
being blamed the carnal mind naturally
casts false lights if you want to know
why God's church usually we have so many
issues with one another watch this this
is crazy
rebellion is as the sin of witchcraft
stubbornness as iniquity and idolatry
those who set themselves against the
government of God have entered into an
alliance with the ark apostate he will
cause everything to appear in a many
thus led by Satan deceived themselves
with the belief that they are in the
service of God in the days of Christ the
Jews obstruct the Jewish scribes and
elders who profess great zeal for the
honor of God crucified his son the same
spirit still exists in the hearts of
those who set themselves to follow their
own will in opposition to the will of
God let me show you an example of false
lines Exodus 16 - the whole congregation
of the children of Israel murmured
against Moses and Aaron in the
wilderness and the children of Israel
said unto them would to God we had died
by the hand of the Lord in Egypt when we
sat by the fleshpots when we did eat
bread to the four for you have brought
us forth into this wilderness to kill
this whole assembly will hunger
yo yo yo bro I was walking by Moses tent
I was just minding my business and I
ain't trying to kill us with hunger bro
I kid you not on the real yes yes faith
poppies they weren't just talking like
are you trying to kick no they were like
yo the dude is trying to kill us
that's why he hold on wait wait Exodus
17 3 he thought it was just one time no
no no and the people thirsty for water
and the people murmured against Moses
and said where wherefore is it that that
brought us up out of Egypt to kill us we
and our children and our cattle yo bro I
was walking by Moses 10 again and this
time he didn't just say he's gonna kill
us and this spread through the camp so
that the children of Israel murmured not
one person here or one person there the
entire camp he's trying to kill us
remember korah's rebellion yeah is it a
small thing that they brought us up out
of land of if a land brought us up of a
land that flows with milk and honey to
kill us in the wilderness
except I'll make thyself a prince over
us moreover thou has not brought us into
the land that flows with milk and honey
you have not given us an inheritance
will you put out our eyes the eyes of
these men also we will not come up they
were like yo I'm telling you Moses Moses
man he will put your eyes yo that guy is
crazy I heard it myself yo sauce light
check this up you know what I'm having a
story right that I the ground opened up
and God swallowed up the rebels and then
the very next day the children of Israel
murmured said Moses you have killed the
people of the Lord this is this one is
amazing notwithstanding you would not go
up but rebelled against the commandment
of the Lord your God you murmured in
your tents and said because the Lord
hated us yo I wasn't walking by Moses 10
and Moses was talking with God and guess
what God said he said I hate them I
heard it with my own ears how is the
devil so powerful that he couldn't make
one believe that God hates filter carnal
mind so guess what guess what everyone
praise God you know my Jesus came into
this world right why did Jesus come into
this world okay but think about what
we've been talking about why did he come
into the world because Satan had been
putting his father in a lot false light
so Jesus comes to be the true light yes
yes yes check this out guys
Christ came into the world to represent
the father to man for Satan had
presented him before the world in a
because Satan's superpower is false
lights you see through false light Satan
can turn the best of friends into
enemies through false life Satan can
take the the best of church members and
make them hate each other
through false light if the enemy can do
so much because he doesn't need to
depend upon truth he just picks the
filter and says yep because God is a God
of justice of terrible majesty who has
power to destroy as well as preserve man
Satan cause men to regard him with fear
to look upon him as a tyrant remember
jesus said he that seen me hath seen the
whole father
so Amen Jesus came into the world except
there was a problem because at the end
of Jesus life Pilate answered and said
again unto them what will you that I do
unto him who you call King of the Jews
and they cried out what hold on guys
wait a second how in the world are the
Jews calling out for the crucifixion of
Jesus then Pilate said unto them why
what evil has he done I want you to
notice how the next how the next
sentence goals and they cried out the
more exceedingly crucify him now did you
get what just happened here do you get
what just happened why do they cry out
more exceedingly why didn't they cry out
the same you know he asked what should I
do with him they said crucifying and
then he asks what what evil has he done
and when they heard that question they
were like they lost him they were like
crucify him why let me tell you why in
99 Christ had been accused of falsely
claiming to forgive sins he had been
accused of eating with publicans and
sinners he had been accused of laboring
on the Sabbath he had been accused of
working the power of days above he had
been accused of breaking Jewish
tradition he had been accused of
destroying the temple and building it
again in three days or claiming to build
it again in three days he had been
accused of being of claiming to be a
prophet he'd been accused of falsely
claiming to be the Son of God he had
been accused of not paying taxes he had
been accused on the question of divorce
he had been accused
of hypocrisy he had been accused of of
eating with sinners he had been accused
of over how do you find 40 things to
accuse Jesus of you gotta stop and think
about that for moment if you try to come
up with 40 things to accuse me of or I
try to come up with 40 things to accuse
you of we might probably do pretty good
because guess what we are all sinners
but how is your mind so corrupted that
you can find 40 things or more to accuse
Jesus the perfect one of so all these
little false lights that kept going
against Christ yeah man
did you hear yeah he broke the Sabbath
what okay let me tuck that away yo did
you hear what he he was talking about
eating flesh and garden what whoa so by
the time it comes to the crib
to that scene when they cry out crucify
him they're not just like oh you know
what
we think this would look good in a book
down in the future that we were really
mad at him no they cried out crucify him
because of all the things they had heard
and never went to Jesus to saying Jesus
did did you say that we have to eat
flesh and blood the human heart tends to
vilify what it does not understand Jesus
said or the Bible says in John 1 for in
him was life and the life was the light
of men the light shine in the darkness
and the darkness what comprehended it
not so what do they do check this up and
he said these things unto them the
scribes and Pharisees began to urge him
vehemently and to provoke him to speak
of many things laying wait for him and
seeking to catch something out of his
mouth that they might want accuse him
Luke 20 20 they watched him and sent
forth spies which had feigned themselves
just men that they might take hold of
his words so that they might
never him unto the power and authority
of the governor Satan will try to set
you up she says here I'm just gonna read
the bottom part here their criticism of
Christ and his disciples was severe and
denouncing and placed them in a wat what
is Satan's super power false lights so
check us out Christ ascends to heaven
amen
remember our opening Scripture who is
this King of glory the Lord strong and
mighty the Lord mighty in what battle so
hold on a second check this out guys how
was Jesus entering heaven mighty in
battle when he has just been accused of
all this stuff and died put to death at
the cross
how was he mighty in battle I want you
to think about that
Deuteronomy 2010 says this when you come
against the city to fight against it
propane then proclaim peace unto it hold
on a second God's method of dealing with
his enemies when you come against the
city to fight against it the first thing
I want you to do is proclaim so the
Jesus come to this earth to fight did
Jesus come to this earth to fight yeah
and what's the first thing he does he
proclaims peace the gospel listen to me
beloved
great peace have they which love thy law
and nothing shall what nothing shall
cause them before nothing shall offend
them listen guys what is the law that
Jesus was talking about remember the
carnal mind is not subject to the law of
God what is the law Romans 13:10 says
love worketh no ill to his neighbor
therefore love is the fulfilling of the
law so the carnal man
is not subject to loving you guys he did
here like I said the colonel mind is not
subject to loving no the colonel mind
wants to see evil yeah yeah yeah why
because the carnal mind is a mind that
hates and a mind that hates wants to
find reason to hate so now I've got this
filter that says this is why I don't
like you this is this filter
they never get out of the way it's not
about you it's about how the enemy is
seeking to destroy relationships what is
love love suffers long love is kind love
Envy if not love vaunteth not itself is
not puffed up does not behave itself
unseemly seeketh not her own is not
easily provoked thinketh no evil bears
all things believes all things hopes all
things endures all things let me ask you
a question
the greatest text that reveals God's
battle plan is John 3:16 for so do you
remember that Christ was the only one
allowed into the counsels of God and
therefore he knew God's battle plan yeah
so guess what if you want to know God's
battle plan where do you need to go in
counsel with God
remember the disciples were all fighting
with each other I don't like you yeah
what I don't like you I mean think about
that we're followers of Christ by the
way I don't like you
you know what Christ invites them to do
invites them to go to a place called the
Upper Room if I might let's just change
the name of that Upper Room to the war
room
that was the war room that's where they
fought the battle in the war room social
acts 1:14 these are continued with one
Accord in prayer and supplication and
what happened as a result of their
prayer and supplication what happened to
the fighting and division among them
what happened what happened to the
filters in which they sought other year
Peter I know who you are
yeah John I know who you are yes I'm
what happened to those filters they were
gone and beloved check this out when a
filter is room
moved you can mend a relationship in
five minutes or less when a filter is
there there's really no hope you might
think I've mended the relationship but
you haven't it's a lie you might be like
[Laughter]
nothing's going on it's just another
fake moment happy Sabbath the day you're
not here so listen to this powerful
statement when the day of Pentecost was
fully come they were all with one Accord
and suddenly there came a sound from
heaven as a rush and rushing mighty wind
and it filled all the house where they
were sitting
this came upon the praying disciples
with a fullness that reached every heart
aim and everyone heaven rejoice in being
able to pour out the riches of the
spirits grace amen everyone words of
penitence and interrogation mingled with
songs of praise
yeah yeah words of penitence and
interrogation so Peter hold on before
the Holy Spirit is poured out I think do
you remember what you said to me five
weeks ago because I'm not praying with
you until you admit what you said so so
just hold on Holy Spirit please wait
Peter no no no no it doesn't say that
does it I have added the word
interrogation in accidentally the word
is confession they were not concerned
with well you Urim you were wrong here
yeah I was okay all right now okay now
no they were like look you're a sinner
I'm a sinner let's call it even
you're a sinner I'm a sinner we both are
in and they need of the grace of God so
if we can acknowledge hey you know what
I'm no better than you you're no better
than me God hasn't work for us to do
let's not try to interrogate each other
let's be about our father's business
that's what happened in the war room
listen revelation 12 one through four
speaks about this woman who is the
church listen carefully guys this is
coming down to us now I need you to
focus
by the way I need you to get out of the
way revelation 12 there's this woman who
is pregnant with a child that child is
the child of Jesus Christ and the Bible
says that as she is giving birth to this
child that dragon is standing before her
trying to devour the child I have a
question for you who is the woman the
church it's Jesus Christ the last child
she had is that a trick question for you
earlier are you thinking is Jesus Christ
the last child she had nope
every time a person is born again
the church has given birth to a
so the devil the devil does not want the
church bearing children so he has to
come up with a form of please follow me
here he has to come up with a form of
birth control feeling yeah yeah no no no
listen we can't have you having kids so
we've got to find a way to stop you from
bearing children why because that's the
Great Commission go ye into all the
world bring people into the church have
people born again when people are born
again they are a new creation
remember how Satan felt about the
creation of man he feels the very same
way about the recreation of man so if he
sees wait a minute the church hold on
wait a minute
the church is planning to do a big
recreation event nah we can't have that
the church is planning to reach out and
to witness and to reach its community
nah we can't have that and beloved now
you and I can know oh yeah this is to be
expected if that's what the devil did in
heaven over the creation process of man
we can expect that he would do the same
thing when we are planning a recreation
process this is Satan at work search
Satan's battle plan is to accuse one
another Matthew 24:12 because iniquity
shall abound the love of many shall wax
cold now 2/6 psalm sixty four verse six
listen to what Satan will inspire you to
do they search out iniquities they
accomplish a diligent search both inward
thoughts of them and the heart is deep
in other words you I got light that's
what Satan cousin man this is light hey
look at this person and look at that
person and he goes on this accusation
Paige in order to separate brothers who
love each other let me ask you do you
think the angels in heaven love one
another do you think it was a time that
wicked angels now were in sweet
fellowship with angels in heaven do you
think there was a time yeah they didn't
always it wasn't always as we there was
a time that these angels were the best
of friends and Lucifer the mastermind
was able to separate the chiefest of
friends beloved listen to me I am
pleading with you as a church let us see
what the enemy is up to listen I am
almost done but this is important enough
for me to go I am almost done
Philippians 2 to fulfilling my joy that
ye be like-minded having the same love
being of one Accord and one mind God
calls us to what everyone to love listen
to me I know I know what it is look if
you're looking at someone right now and
you're like yeah I hate you guess what
you're wearing your hearing off you're
wearing green filters God does not see
us for what we are but for what we can
be in him you may be looking at someone
with problems I'm not saying no one has
problems what I'm saying is what filter
are you looking through are you looking
through the filter of love or are you
looking through the filter of the carnal
mind that's why the Bible says let this
mind be in you which was also in Christ
Jesus he's asking us he's saying listen
you cannot see people differently with
the carnal mind you have to get rid of
the filter and the only way to get rid
of the filter is to get a new mind
because when you get a new mind you now
see people as Jesus sees them listen
Elvis I have a series of Courts I'm
gonna read to you and then we're gonna
wrap this thing up you got and then I'm
gonna give you a challenge you have to
hear these beloved Christians should
regard it as a religious duty to repress
the spirit of envy or emulation should
rejoice in the superior reputation or
prosperity of their brethren I'll let
you know when Jackie you can sit there
though they should rejoice in the
superior reputation beloved come on come
on tell me what is the carnal mind like
you're not superior than me you're not
better than it's that very attitude
listen guys I'm not the best preacher in
the world please I rebuke you
it's a congregate it's a comedy I'm not
the best preacher in the world she's not
the best musician in the world you are
there are not the best musicians
musicians in the world you're not the
best deacon in the world you are not the
best elders in the world you're not the
best church member in the work you're
not the best Church in the world you are
the best Church of it you're never you
David
yet for right we are not the best
anything and once we realize we're not
the best anything we're not gonna have
issues with other people who may
exemplify a gift that might be all
manners Wow
she says they should rejoice in the
superior reputation or prosperity of
their brethren even when in their own
character or achievements seem to be
cast in the shade it was the pride and
ambition cherish in the heart of Satan
that banished him from heaven these
evils are deeply rooted in our fallen
nature and if not removed they will
overshadow every good and noble quality
and bring forth envy and strife as their
veil for results remember Saul and David
remember the sort of Saul and David you
know what Saul was wearing filters one
verse got solved first angle 89 and saw
I'd David from that time forward
that's a funny to me that is so funny
like Saul I David from that day on
it's just every time I read it and saw I
David and what was he eyeing David
because they were singing David has
slain his ten thousands while Saul has
slain his soul began to see David
through a filter love it listen to me
that is the work of the carnal mind
please church I hope right now that that
every one of you are loving me as I am
loving every one of you because I hope
at the end of this none of you come and
say pastor you were talking about me
because I am NOT get out of the way I
will smile with you afterward and hug
you and let you know him it was it's not
about you II wrestle not against flesh
and blood but against spiritual
wickedness in high places listen false
lights and filters come in many forms it
can be jealousy it can be racism yes
racism you're a different color than me
and I don't like that it can be pride it
can be power there are multiple false
filters beloved that we have to
understand that is the way the enemy
comes in from whence comes Wars and
Fighting's among you come they not hence
even of your lusts that war in your
members submit yourself to God resist
the devil and he will flee from you
speak evil of one another they love it
listen to me we have all we have all
been guilty of this before oh-o-oh
been guilty of this before God forgive
us for playing into the devil's hands
God forgive us for having our eyes
blinded and not seeing what the enemy
seeks to do also that we will not be out
doing our father's business report and
we were important I heard for I heard
that
on many of many fearing on every syde
report they say and we were reported all
my familiars watched from our halt and
saying peradventure he will be enticed
and we shall prevail against him and we
shall take our revenge on him this
should not be our attitude listen in
past ages there have been those who have
exercised the capabilities and powers in
doing a work by the Holy Spirit by the
help of the Holy Spirit which
constituted them laborers together with
God but there have also been those who
have criticized their work and rejected
the messages which they bore so it is
today there are those in responsible
positions who by their word and actions
sow seeds of doubt and unbelief these
seeds are called tears by our Lord and
those who sow it are under the guidance
of evil angels that's rough stuff guys
they are at work both openly at sea and
secretly seeking to counteract the work
which God has appointed his divine
agencies to perform through human
agencies all who do this work see this
works see with defective and perverted
eyesight did you catch that guys all who
do this work see with defective and
perverted eyesight their imagination is
inspired by satanic agencies and they
see many things in a ok put on your seat
belts if you didn't put them on before
we're wrapping up I promise you the
pastoral wrap up but you have to hear
this it is not God's plan that reports
regarding the work of his servants shall
be passed from one to another my
brethren when someone comes to you with
an accusation against a fellow worker
how many workers do we have in here how
many workers do we have in here oh how
many workers do we have in here if
you're a Christian you're a worker how
many workers that we have in here
it is not God's plan that reports
regarding the work of his servant shall
be passed from one to another my
brethren when someone comes to you with
an accusation against the fellow work or
say to him let's read this together I
don't want to be I don't leave what
let's read it together
say to him have you gone to the one you
are accusing in the way in which Christ
has told you to go if you have not done
this okay I hear like five like ten
people reading why don't you want to say
this lecture if you have not done this I
am not at liberty to what listen to what
you have to say about him Wow
those who are Bible Christians will do
as Christ has directed if his directions
were followed many wounds would be cured
that are now left to fester and break
out until they are incurable to follow
the course laid down by the great
teacher who never airs in council is the
only way to stop the false tongue and
cause criticism and accusing to cease
floating rumors are often the Destroyers
of unity among brethren there are some
who watched with open mind and ears to
catch flying scandal they gather up
little incidents which may be trifling
in themselves but which are repeated and
exaggerated until a man is made an
offender forward their model seems to be
reports and we were reported these tale
bearers are doing Satan's with
surprising fidelity little knowing how
offensive their course is to God if they
would spend half the energy and zeal
that is given to this unholy work in
examining their own hearts our own
hearts they would find so much to do to
cleanse their souls from impurity that
they would have no time or disposition
to criticize their brethren the door of
the mind should be closed against they
say or I have heard why should we not
instead of allowing jealousy or evil
surmisings to come into our hearts go to
our brethren and ask and after frankly
but kindly setting before them the
things which we have heard - there
detrimental to their character and
influence prey with them and for them
while we cannot fellowship with those
who are the bitterest enemies of Christ
we should cultivate the spirit of
meekness and love that characterized our
master I love that thinketh no evil and
is not easily provoked Christ laid down
rules Ellen White is preaching now okay
I'm just listen to her Christ lay down
rules to prevent unhappy divisions but
how many in our churches have followed
his directions Matthew 18:15
217 is quoted and then she says if these
instructions which Christ has given were
followed out in the spirit that every
true Christian should have if each one
aggrieved would go to the offending
member and seek in kindness to correct
the wrong by privately telling him of
his of his fault many a grievous child
would be averted when anyone comes to a
minister or two men in position of trust
with complaints about a brother or
sister let them ask and this is said
again if he has failed to carry out
particular the particular of this
instruction do not listen to a word of
his complaints refuse to take up a
report against your brother or sister in
the faith if members of the church go
entirely contrary to these rules they
make themselves subject of church
discipline and should be put under the
censure of the church this matter so
plainly taught in the lessons of Christ
have been passed over with strange
indifference the church has either
neglected her work entirely or have done
it with hardness and severity wounding
and bruising Souls measures should be
taken to correct this cruel spirit of
criticism of judging one another's
motives as though Christ had revealed to
mend the hearts of their brethren the
neglect of doing the right with wisdom
and grace the work that ought to that
have been done has left churches weak
inefficient and almost Chrysler's guys I
don't know about you I don't want a
crisis Church no no no I know about you
I know you don't want a crisis church so
beloved if you and I don't want a crisis
Church let's do what Christ called us to
do if this instruction is not heated
because we choose to disobey doing the
very opposite of that which Christ has
told us to do how would it be with our
religious life we shall be found
communicating to others to one another
the faults of our brethren in the church
and those even reports will spread this
evil surmising and suspicions of
dishonesty will spread from lip to lip
notwithstanding the plain directions
given by Christ not to sow the seeds of
evil by speaking evil of our brethren
those who pursue a course contrary to
this instruction are creating in their
own hearts the evil they condemn in
others and thus are themselves brought
under condemnation the Bible plan of
avoiding and remedying difficulties
among brethren is the only safe plan
Christ is grieved to see some disregard
this instruction follow their own plans
plans opposed to his when those who
claim to be Christians walk in harmony
with divine instruction there will be
far less evil surmising and evil
speaking in the church can someone say
amen to this but nah but I got one more
quote if Satan can imply it can employ
professed believers to act as accusers
of the Brethren he is greatly pleased
for those who do this are just as truly
serving him as was Judas when he
betrayed Christ although they may be
doing it ignorant Lee Satan is no less
active now than in Christ's day and
those who lend themselves to do his work
will manifest his spirit you guys do not
be a traitor
did you catch what I just said do not be
a a traitor because that's what the
devil does
The Devil's at all those who speak those
who think and speak evil of their fellow
laborers opened the minds of false
reports and taking up a reproach against
his neighbor grieve the spirit of God
and put Christ to open shame are you
ready for the five minute challenge
there are many of them
dwelling on little trials said the angel
legions of evil angels are around you
and are trying to press in their awful
darkness that you may be ensnared and
taking you suffer your mind to be
diverted too readily from the work of
preparation and the all-important truths
of these last days and you dwell upon
little trials and go into minut
particulars of little difficulties to
explain them to the satisfaction of this
one or that anyone ever been guilty of
that conversation has been protracted
for conversation has been protracted for
no we stay conversation has been
protracted for between the parties
concerned and not only has their time
been wasted but the servants of God are
held to listen to them when the hearts
of both parties are unsubdued by grace
if pride and selfishness were laid aside
you mean I could've done this sermon in
five minutes five minutes would remove
most difficulties hours have been spent
in justifying self which has grieved
angels and displease God I saw that God
will not wait and bow down and listen to
long justifications and he did not want
his service to do so and precious time
be wasted that should be spent in
showing transgressors the errors of
their way and pulling Souls out of the
fire why five minutes guys because it's
very simple he that covered the
transgressions seeketh love but he that
repeated the matters separated very
friends or we can read it this way
hatred stirreth up strides but love
cover it all sins if I really love you
all I need to hear from you is a you
know what Matt let's let's squash this
and let's move on I don't need you to I
don't need you to grovel oh you know and
then and I apologize I don't need that
because that's not what I'm after I'm
after souls and you should be after
souls and if souls is the most important
thing let's not waste time trying to
explain to each other
no you know what is what I meant look I
you know at this point I don't care what
you meant if you are saying hey I'm down
to finish the work forget about it
because that's what love does love
doesn't take an account and say well
until you make XY and Z and do this and
do that and bow and grovel then then
maybe we can work together no love is
I'm gonna tell you something listen five
minutes if your intent is to go approve
yourself right
don't go if your intent is to prove your
brother or sister wrong don't go if your
intent is
your brother or sister injured defamed
humiliated or to lose don't go if your
intent is to reconcile then go it will
take five minutes and five minutes is
for those who are stubborn I had an
incident this morning right before the
divine service there was some conflict
and in a matter of two minutes that
conflict was done I'm talking about a
conflict that's been going on for a
little while and in a matter of two
minutes without words even being spoken
all of a sudden what looked like a great
big wall how is his wallet Jericho gonna
fall to me it wasn't even it was
actually like about ten seconds boom
done wall down you guys when we try to
prove I was right and you were wrong and
until you admit that I was right and you
were wrong we get nowhere love says that
we have a mission bygones are bygones
let's move forward and but i'ma say this
I'm finished I'm not even reading that
I'll just tell you something
Nehemiah had a work to do Nehemiah was
called by God to do a work and I believe
that every one of us in here have been
called by God to do a work but you know
Nehemiah had enemies you know his
enemies did to him he would say hey he
was up in a wall come down come down
Nehemiah said I'm not coming down from
this wall I have a work to do and and I
will stay focused on the work of God and
I'm saying this today beloved I'm not
coming down I have a work to do
I have a commission to accomplish
something here and I'm asking you as a
church my brothers and sisters those of
you in this church that maybe like a
pastor and even those of you maybe like
home pastor I'm asking all of you let's
do this together because when we don't
do that the enemy gets the victory and
all of us lose